A Guide to the Population Council records, Lapham and Van Wie Files, Accession 2, RG 2, Series 8 FA1302
Rockefeller Archive Center
Population Council records, Lapham and Van Wie Files, Accession 2, RG 2, Series 8
1965-1977
Rockefeller Archive Center
Population Council
Van Wie, Diane
Lapham, Robert
FA1302
7.52 Cubic Feet 16 legal sized document boxes.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This material was transferred to RAC in 1979 by the Population Council and ingested by RAC as Accession 1979:004.
Arrangement
The Lapham and Van Wie files are arranged into two subseries:
1. Country Files, 1970-1976
2. Subject Files, 1965-1977
Scope and Contents
The Lapham and Van Wie files include field staff files from the Research and Evaluation Unit of the Population Council. Major topics include the evaluation of field programs, Gavin and Jones - Indonesia correspondence, records of the Taylor-Berelson Maternal and Child Health-Family Planning (MCH/FP) program, and research on fertility projection research.
Population and Population Control; Birth control -- Evaluation
- Country Files, 1970-1976; 1; 3.77 Cubic Feet 8 legal document boxes
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically by geographic area.
  - Bangladesh, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bangladesh - "Beyond", 1975 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bangladesh - Field Staff, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bangladesh - ISRT Consulting Assignment, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bangladesh - Nutrition Qaire, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Bangladesh - Population Council/Colombia Collaboration, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bangladesh - Resource Support Services Report, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Brazil, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Cameroon, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - China - Health and Nutritional Factors in Early Childhood Development, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Colombia, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Colombia - Bogota Report, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Colombia - National Follow-Up Survey, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Colombia - Profamilia, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Dominican Republic, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Dominican Republic - Follow-Up Survey, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Dominican Republic - Report, 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Egypt, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - El Salvador, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - France, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Guadeloupe, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - India, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Indonesia, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 23-24)
  - Indonesia - Biden Orientation Course, undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Indonesia - BKKBN, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Indonesia - BKKBN - Agreement Revisions, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Indonesia - BKKBN - Participants for Bogue Workshop, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Indonesia - Ecological Survey, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Indonesia - Institute of Public Heath (Surabaya), 1972 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Indonesia - LENKAS, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Indonesia - Maps, undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Indonesia - Mojokerto, 1972-1976 (Box 2, Folder 33-34, Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Indonesia - Mojokerto Code Book, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 36-40)
  - Indonesia - Mojokerto Project - HPCU Survey, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Indonesia - Mojokerto Village Ecological Survey, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Indonesia - National Program Cost Analysis, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Indonesia - Planning Meetings on Implementation and Operation, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Indonesia - Surabaya Meeting - Duplicate Material, undated (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Indonesia - World Fertility Project - Milk Powder Distribution, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Iran, 1970-1975 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Iran - Benefits Project (Gillespie), 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Iran - Esfahan Project, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Iran - Frejka Project, 1971-1975 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Iran - Field Staff Correspondence, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Iran - Isfahan Findings, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Iran - Model Sharistan Paper, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Kenya, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Korea, 1969-1976 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Korea - Field Staff, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Korea - John Ross Project, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Mauritius, 1974-1975 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Malaysia, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Mexico, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - Morocco, 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - Morocco - Field Staff, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Morocco - Reports, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - Nigeria, 1974-1975 (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Nigeria - Background Data, undated (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - North Africa, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - Philippines, 1974-1976 (Box 5, Folder 67-68)
  - Philippines - Bohol Province, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 69-71)
  - Philippines - Budget Revision, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 72)
  - Philippines - Laing Assignment, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 73-74)
  - Philippines - Maps, undated (Box 6, Folder 75)
  - Philippines - Proposal, 1973-1974 (Box 7, Folder 76-77)
  - Philippines - Research Notes, undated (Box 7, Folder 78-79)
  - Philippines - Service Statistics, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 80)
  - Singapore, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 81)
  - Sri Lanka, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 82)
  - Taiwan, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 83)
  - Taiwan - Field Staff Correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 84)
  - Taiwan - Grants, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 85)
  - Taiwan - Office Field Reports, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 86)
  - Thailand, 1972-1976 (Box 7, Folder 87)
  - Tunisia, 1975-1976 (Box 8, Folder 88)
  - Tunisia - Chekir Request, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 89)
  - Tunisia - Guidelines, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 90)
  - Tunisia - LeMelle, Wilbert (Ford Foundation), 1975-1976 (Box 8, Folder 91)
  - Tunisia - Physician Questionnaires, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 92)
  - Tunisia - Tarifia, Chedly (SEPEN), 1975 (Box 8, Folder 93)
  - Turkey, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 94)
  - Turkey - Bibliographies, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 95)
  - Turkey - Development Foundation of Turkey (DFT), 1976 (Box 8, Folder 96)
  - Turkey - Evaluation Unit Staffing, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 97)
  - Turkey - Field Workers, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 98)
  - Turkey - Service Program Plan - Seyhan Province, undated (Box 8, Folder 99)
  - Turkey - PCM Trip, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 100)
  - Turkey - PCM Trip (Peter Miller), 1974 (Box 8, Folder 101)
  - Turkey - Trip Report, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 102)
  - Turkey - Vital Rates, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 103)
  - Turkey - Yozgat Project Report, 1974-1975 (Box 8, Folder 104)
  - Turkey - Yozgat Questionnaire, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 105)
  - Venezuela, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 106)
- Subject Files, 1965-1977; 2; 4.24 Cubic Feet 9 legal document boxes
  Arranged alphabetically by topic.
  - Abortion, 1974-1976 (Box 8, Folder 107)
  - Abortion - Joint Program for the Study of Abortion (JPSA), 1971 (Box 8, Folder 108)
  - Abortion - Research Meeting, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 109)
  - Advisory Committee Meeting, 1973-1975 (Box 9, Folder 110)
  - Aid, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 111)
  - Calculation of Patient Visits, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 112)
  - Community Based Distribution, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 113)
  - Continuation Rates, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 114)
  - Copper-T, 1971-1975 (Box 9, Folder 115)
  - Correspondence, 1971-1975 (Box 9, Folder 116)
  - Cost Studies - Westinghouse Population Center, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 117)
  - Data on Contraceptive Users, 1975-1976 (Box 9, Folder 118)
  - Ecological Analysis - Statistical Methods, undated (Box 9, Folder 119)
  - Ecological Survey, 1972-1973 (Box 9, Folder 120)
  - Evaluation - Alam, Sadre, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 121)
  - Evaluation - Book List, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 122)
  - Evaluation - Filing System, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 123)
  - Evaluation - Follow Up Survey (Miller Draft), undated (Box 9, Folder 124)
  - Evaluation - Health Forms, undated (Box 10, Folder 125)
  - Evaluation - Lapham Memoranda, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 126)
  - Evaluation - Lapham et al. Paper, 1973-1974 (Box 10, Folder 127-128)
  - Evaluation - Library, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 129)
  - Evaluation - Miller, Peter, 1972-1974 (Box 10, Folder 130)
  - Evaluation - Requests for Materials, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 131)
  - Evaluation - Seminar, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 132)
  - Evaluation - Sullivan Memoranda, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 133)
  - Evaluation - Taylor, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 134)
  - Evaluation - Treadway, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 135)
  - Evaluation - Van Wie Memoranda, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 136)
  - Evaluation - Wolfere, David, 1971-1973 (Box 10, Folder 137-138)
  - Evaluation Theory - Finney: Problems, Data, and Interference, undated (Box 10, Folder 139)
  - Evaluation Theory - Greenberg: Evaluation of Social Programs, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 140)
  - Evaluation Theory - Mauldin: Measurement and Evaluation of National Family Planning Programs, 1972-1973 (Box 10, Folder 141)
  - Evaluation Theory - Whishik: Group-Specific Fertility Patterns, undated (Box 10, Folder 142)
  - Ford Foundation Small Grants Program, 1971-1972 (Box 10, Folder 143)
  - Gavin Jones - Articles, 1974-1975 (Box 11, Folder 144)
  - Gavin Jones - Correspondence, 1971-1976 (Box 11, Folder 145-147)
  - Gavin Jones - Field Reports, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 148)
  - Health Practices, 1972-1973 (Box 11, Folder 149)
  - ICCR, 1975-1976 (Box 11, Folder 150)
  - Inter-Project Comparisons - Density and Dispersion, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 151)
  - Intern Project, 1971-1972 (Box 11, Folder 152)
  - Intern - Claude Paulet (Morocco), 1971-1973 (Box 11, Folder 153)
  - International Pregnancy Advisory Services (IPAS), 1975 (Box 11, Folder 154)
  - International Women's Year Conference, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 155)
  - IUD Questionnaires, undated (Box 11, Folder 156)
  - Knowledge, Aptitude, Practice (KAP), 1971-1975 (Box 11, Folder 157-158)
  - Knowledge, Aptitude, Practice (KAP) - Comments, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 159)
  - Knowledge, Aptitude, Practice (KAP) - Family Size Attitudes, 1967-1969 (Box 12, Folder 160)
  - Knowledge, Aptitude, Practice (KAP) - Model Questionnaire (First Draft), undated (Box 12, Folder 161)
  - Knowledge, Aptitude, Practice (KAP) - PopLab Monograph 5, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 162)
  - Knowledge, Aptitude, Practice (KAP) - Fertility Health Questionnaire (PCM Draft), 1974 (Box 12, Folder 163)
  - Knowledge, Aptitude, Practice (KAP) - Questionnaires, 1966-1974 (Box 12, Folder 164-167)
  - Knowledge, Aptitude, Practice (KAP) - Wishik: Amount of Contraception Practice, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 168)
  - Knowledge, Aptitude, Practice (KAP) - World Fertility Survey, 1973-1976 (Box 13, Folder 169-170)
  - Life Table Procedures, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 171)
  - Measurement of Nutrition - Anthropometric Measures, 1970-1974 (Box 13, Folder 172)
  - Maternal and Child Health-Family Planning (MCH/FP) Program - Cost Study, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 173)
  - Maternal and Child Health-Family Planning (MCH/FP) Program - Notebook, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 174)
  - Maternal and Child Health-Family Planning (MCH/FP) Program - Service Statistics, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 175)
  - Meetings on Controls, 1973-1975 (Box 13, Folder 176)
  - Migration of Health Personnel from Developing Countries to Developed Countries, 1973-1976 (Box 13, Folder 177)
  - Model Forms Comparisions, undated (Box 13, Folder 178)
  - Mini-Lap, 1974-1975 (Box 13, Folder 179)
  - NICHHD, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 180)
  - Non-Clinical Distribution, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 181)
  - Oral Contraceptives, 1975-1976 (Box 13, Folder 182)
  - Pill Part of Contraceptive Technology Paper (Bruce Schearer), 1975 (Box 14, Folder 183)
  - Pill Questionnaires, undated (Box 14, Folder 184)
  - PopLab, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 185)
  - Postpartum, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 186)
  - Program Impact - Births Averted by Abortion, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 187)
  - Program Impact - Data Requirements, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 188)
  - Research and Evaluation (R&E) Luncheons, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 189)
  - Research and Evaluation (R&E) Program Review, 1975-1976 (Box 14, Folder 190)
  - Sample Design, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 191)
  - Sampling Error, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 192)
  - Sampling Error Calculations, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 193)
  - Tribal Sampling - Fellegi-Krotki Paper, 1972-1973 (Box 14, Folder 194)
  - Saturation Effort Program, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 195)
  - Service Statistices, 1969-1974 (Box 14, Folder 196)
  - Socio-Economic Models, undated (Box 14, Folder 197)
  - Sterilization, 1975-1976 (Box 14, Folder 198)
  - Sterilization Comparative Study, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 199)
  - Studies - Fertility Reduction Model (Miller, Tao, Lapham), 1973-1975 (Box 15, Folder 200-203)
  - Supervision, 1973 (Box 15, Folder 204)
  - Survey Data - Application of Life Table Methods, 1972 (Box 15, Folder 205)
  - Follow Up Survey - Postpartum Instruction Manual, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 206)
  - Follow Up Survey - Sivin LFU Comments, 1972 (Box 15, Folder 207)
  - Follow Up Survey - Wells: Measurement Problems, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 208)
  - Taylor-Berelson - Budgets, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 209)
  - Taylor-Berelson - Costs, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 210)
  - Taylor-Berelson - Country Comparison, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 211)
  - Taylor-Berelson - Glossaries, undated (Box 16, Folder 212)
  - Taylor-Berelson - Newsletters, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 213)
  - Taylor-Berelson - Operational Charts, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 214)
  - Taylor-Berelson - Population Growth Estimate (PGE), 1973-1974 (Box 16, Folder 215)
  - Taylor-Berelson - Records and Record System, 1972-1973 (Box 16, Folder 216)
  - Tulane University - Family Planning Factbook, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 217)
  - Vital Rate Estimation - Caldwell: African Fertility, undated (Box 16, Folder 218)
  - Vital Rate Estimation - Demographic Theory, 1967-1971 (Box 16, Folder 219)
  - Vital Rate Estimation - Population Growth Estimate (PGE), 1961-1973 (Box 16, Folder 220)
  - Vital Rate Estimation - Pregnancy History Approach, 1971-1975 (Box 16, Folder 221)
  - Vital Rate Estimation - Sample Survey Methodology, 1965 (Box 16, Folder 222)
  - Vital Rate Estimation - Seltzer: Birth Rate, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 223)
  - Vital Rate Estimation - Seltzer: Population Growth Estimate (PGE) Cost and Effectiveness, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 224)
  - Vital Rate Estimation - Shorter: Household Inventories and Retrospective Histories, undated (Box 16, Folder 225)
  - Vital Rate Estimation - Special Registration, 1965 (Box 16, Folder 226)
  - World Fertility Survey, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 227)
  - World Health Organization - Reports, 1965-1966 (Box 16, Folder 228)